Md. Ahsan Habib,CSM®,CSCP™

Dhaka, Bangladesh



habib.heromotocorp@gmail.com



01711712466



linkedin.com/in/md-ahsan-habib-csm%C2%AEcscp%E2%84%A2-3603b1144

Summary

Started career in BATB. as territory officer. After 2 years of my career i joined at Nitol-Niloy Group as an area manager .After that I joined a largest tobacco company which is Dhaka Tobacco as a territory manager .After that i was join in a winning team which is Robi Axiata LTD as a sales manager. Now i am working with REDX logistics as a regional manager.

Experience



Regional Head

REDX

Jan 2022 - Present (8 months +)

- Coordinating Outside Dhaka Operations & specially looking after Greater Dhaka region and Sylhet region.
- Maintaining regular Hub operations.
- Monitor and ensure 100% delivery success Ratio.
- Ensure proper hub management and operations by closely working with zonal operation leads.
- Managing team to ensure sustainable growth.
- Supervising and training Hub workforce and rider behavioral issues.
- Keep close communication with Hub In Charge in mitigating day to day crisis.
- Timely update on regional reporting to the concerned management.
- Analyzing trend and partner management to take sustainable growth decision. Ensure business development target of the Zone.
- Connecting with concerned stakeholders in managing issues and further resolution.
- Maintaining metrics and analyzing data to assess performance and implement improvements.
- Time to time develop people in bringing operational excellence.
- Meet up SLA at regular basis.
- · Ensure Hub compliance at all segment.
- Maintain Operational Cost.
- Following Up both Rider Retention and Attrition.

- Generate and communicate dynamic reporting as per business requirement.

Zonal Operation Manager

REDX

Nov 2020 - Jan 2022 (1 year 3 months)

- Coordinating Outside Dhaka Operations & specially looking after Rajshahi region.
- Maintaining regular Hub operations.
- Monitor and ensure 100% delivery success Ratio.
- Ensure proper hub management and operations by closely working with Hub In Charge.
- Managing team to ensure sustainable growth.
- Supervising and training Hub workforce and rider behavioral issues.
- Keep close communication with Hub In Charge in mitigating day to day crisis.
- Timely update on zonal reporting to the concerned management.
- Analyzing trend and partner management to take sustainable growth decision. Ensure business development target of the Zone.
- Connecting with concerned stakeholders in managing issues and further resolution.
- Maintaining metrics and analyzing data to assess performance and implement improvements.
- Time to time develop people in bringing operational excellence.
- Meet up SLA at regular basis.
- · Ensure Hub compliance at all segment.
- Maintain Operational Cost.
- Following Up both Rider Retention and Attrition.
- Generate and communicate dynamic reporting as per business requirement.



Sales Manager

Robi Axiata Limited

Aug 2017 - Nov 2020 (3 years 4 months)

-Attain Territory Sales Target (RV & SIM) by ensuring proper distribution of products and implementation of retail channel activities.

- -Develop right distribution (expansion of RV & SIM POS) set-up to optimize availability of products in the Area.
- -Develop and manage the operation of third party distribution channels (RSP) as per the company guidelines.
- -Arrange & Execute Trade marketing activities.
- -Ensure Brand Visibility in POS through Point Of Sales Materials to create TOM.
- -Develop long term business relationship with key channel partners (RV POS & SIM POS) & make them feel they are taken care of specially.
- -Monitor & follow up RSP Sales entry & SAF Submission to ensure 100% Compliance.
- -Set up Customer Service points to ensure best customer experience.
- -Pull and mobilize all necessary resources to attain business objectives.

Ē

Territory Manager

Akij Corporation Limited
Mar 2014 - Sep 2017 (3 years 7 months)

- -Lead the territory Team in implementing territory Distribution & Trade Marketing programs.
- -Translate National & Regional Plans & Strategies at territory level to deliver brand, volume, value and profit objectives
- -Follow-up effective execution of campaign plans and special project initiatives at territory level.
- -Drive on-the-job coaching for development of human resources, i.e. RSS/CMS/BRS/OI, and Distributor Field Forces.
- -Smooth implementation of business cycle activities and project based plan that includes Campaign, Consumer engagement, Trade engagement, merchandising activities in order to achieve brand specific targets.
- -Analyze research information (periodical and ad-hoc) and propose action based plan on the finding to strengthen distribution health parameters and BATB market share.
- -Budgetary control in a way to optimize available resources in line with budget.
- -Ensure all the contractual activities (merchandising agency, activation agency, and depot operation) are done as per plan and provide suggestion to the concerned to improve their service quality.
- -Regularly ensuring that Marketing Top Team is fully informed on brand specific challenges, activities and projects with right reporting and feedback

кнего Area Manager

Hero MotoCorp

Jan 2012 - Feb 2014 (2 years 2 months)

- -Search and expansion of new dealer.
- -Aware about eligibility of dealership.
- -Conduct sales to the dealers Showrooms.
- -Monitor dealers payment procedure and documentation.
- -Collect Market information of Motorcycle Industry; comprising competitors sales, offers, BTL activities, marketing strategy etc.
- -Regularly visiting dealers and own showroom outlets.
- -Monitoring the performance, activities and strategies of dealers to increase sales.
- -Frequently visit for quality of branding at own outlet and dealers outlet.
- -Collecting and maintain all sorts of Data and the overall Motorcycle Industry.
- -Assist in planning, organizing and executing BTL activities and Hero Motor Road Show.
- -Aware about Hero spare parts and influence dealer to sell parts.
- -Preparing daily sales report.
- -Maintaining Information and report regarding Dispatch, Retail stock and Walk in

Territory Officer

BAT

Apr 2009 - Mar 2012 (3 years)

- Sales Focus.
- Coverage, Distribution & Retail management.
- Visibility & Activation.
- Distributor Management.
- Training & People Management.
- Reporting & Systems.
- Distributor Claim Management.
- -Lead the territory Team in implementing territory Distribution & Trade Marketing programs.
- -Translate National & Regional Plans & Strategies at territory level to deliver brand, volume, value and profit objectives
- -Follow-up effective execution of campaign plans and special project initiatives at territory level.
- -Drive on-the-job coaching for development of human resources, i.e. RSS/CMS/BRS/OI, and Distributor Field Forces.
- -Smooth implementation of business cycle activities and project based plan that includes Campaign, Consumer engagement, Trade engagement, merchandising activities in order to achieve brand specific targets.
- -Analyze research information (periodical and ad-hoc) and propose action based plan on the finding to strengthen distribution health parameters and BATB market share.
- -Budgetary control in a way to optimize available resources in line with budget.

- -Ensure all the contractual activities (merchandising agency, activation agency, and depot operation) are done as per plan and provide suggestion to the concerned to improve their service quality.
- -Regularly ensuring that Marketing Top Team is fully informed on brand specific challenges, activities and projects with right reporting and feedback

Education



University of Dhaka

Leadership certificate in managerial communication, Business, Management, Marketing, and Related Support Services May 2016 - Apr 2017



BRAC University

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Marketing/Marketing Management, General 2012 - 2013



Asian University of Bangladesh

Bachelor of Business Administration - BBA, Marketing 2008 - 2012



Alimuddin degree college

HSC, Business studies Jun 2008 - Sep 2008

Licenses & Certifications

- Talent Management Program Hero MotoCorp
- Business communication Hero MotoCorp
- Leadership Skill Development Hero MotoCorp
- - Leadership certificate in managerial communication University of Dhaka
- Time management for personal and professional productivity Coursera
- Certified Leadership Consultant (MCP) Macquarie University
- Direct Support Professional Specialist in Positive Behavior Support (DSP) The University of Sydney Business School

- Stress management First Nations University of Canada
- in Customer Success Management Fundamentals LinkedIn
- Supply Chain Foundations: Managing the Process LinkedIn
- in Supply Chain Foundations LinkedIn
- in Lean Six Sigma Foundations LinkedIn
- in Six Sigma Foundations LinkedIn
- in Understanding Logistics LinkedIn
- in Managing Logistics LinkedIn
- in Managing Stress LinkedIn
- in Managing Stress for Positive Change LinkedIn
- in Speaking Confidently and Effectively LinkedIn
- in Ecommerce Fundamentals LinkedIn
- Marketing Foundations: Ecommerce LinkedIn
- in Leadership Mindsets LinkedIn

Skills

E-Commerce • Management • English • New Business Development • Social Media • Public Speaking • Third-Party Logistics (3PL) • Auditing • Problem Solving • Customer Satisfaction

Honors & Awards

Best sealer award - Quasem drycells
Dec 2010

Best performers award - Niloy Motors LTD

Dec 2013

Highest Data revenue growth - Robi Axiata LTD

Sep 2017

i give MOM 29% growth on data revenue.

Cluster top - Robi Axiata Itd

Dec 2017

Highest growth data and activation

Star performer of Q1 - Robi Axiata ltd

Jan 2018

Higher growth given in every parameter.

Star performer of Q2 - Robi Axiata LTD

Jun 2019

highest data revenue growth in Q2'2019

Star performer of Q'2 - Robi Axiata Limited

Aug 2020